<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<!DOCTYPE bugzilla SYSTEM "http://defect.opensolaris.org/bz/bugzilla.dtd">

<bugzilla version="3.6.5"
          urlbase="http://defect.opensolaris.org/bz/"
          
          maintainer="website-admin@opensolaris.org"
>

    <bug>
          <bug_id>15747</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2010-04-24 18:18:00 +0000</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>RFE: use spellchecker to provide potentially correct search terms</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2010-04-26 12:28:31 +0000</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>2</classification_id>
          <classification>Development</classification>
          <product>opengrok</product>
          <component>webapp</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>ANY/Generic</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>NEW</bug_status>
          
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>---</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Hemang Lavana">HemangLavana</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Trond Norbye">trond.norbye</assigned_to>
          <cc>Lubos.Kosco</cc>
    
    <cc>opengrok-dev</cc>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>71931</commentid>
            <who name="Hemang Lavana">HemangLavana</who>
            <bug_when>2010-04-24 18:18:33 +0000</bug_when>
            <thetext>Google&apos;s &quot;did you mean&quot; feature is very powerful. It allows users to type in search keywords with typos but also adds a line saying &quot;Did you mean to search: xxx&quot; instead of xxy.

A similar feature for code search would be very useful where user may have a typo or may not be sure of what keywords to search for.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>71957</commentid>
            <who name="Lubos Kosco">Lubos.Kosco</who>
            <bug_when>2010-04-26 12:28:31 +0000</bug_when>
            <thetext>Hi Hemang,
I think this is already working partly in opengrok
opengrok uses spell check contrib plugin for lucene to get this done and creates a special index for spellchecker, which we also use as suggest feature
this spell check suggest list will show up when there are no hits for the query

I hope to improve suggest in 1067
If you want to have google suggest like feature, please add yourself to 1067

I think I understand what you meant by this bug ...
If there is an typo in the query, show first two results according to correct spellcheck and then the result for the &quot;faulty&quot; query
I guess it could be done, however we need to research a bit on spellchecking and add support for e.g. english which would work flawlessly before adding it to the search page results. 
Current spellchecker only compares the word(s) from the query with the index words, it doesn&apos;t do proper english(or other language) spellchecking.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>

</bugzilla>