<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<!DOCTYPE bugzilla SYSTEM "http://defect.opensolaris.org/bz/bugzilla.dtd">

<bugzilla version="3.6.5"
          urlbase="http://defect.opensolaris.org/bz/"
          
          maintainer="website-admin@opensolaris.org"
>

    <bug>
          <bug_id>16375</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2010-06-24 21:52:00 +0000</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>build config (nbproject/project.properties) makes wrong assumptions about ant.jar location</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2010-06-25 13:52:15 +0000</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>2</classification_id>
          <classification>Development</classification>
          <product>opengrok</product>
          <component>build</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>ANY/Generic</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>NEW</bug_status>
          
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>trivial</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>---</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Christian Lohmaier">cloph</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Trond Norbye">trond.norbye</assigned_to>
          <cc>Lubos.Kosco</cc>
    
    <cc>opengrok-dev</cc>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>74758</commentid>
            <who name="Christian Lohmaier">cloph</who>
            <bug_when>2010-06-24 21:52:07 +0000</bug_when>
            <thetext>The netbeans-property file (nbproject/project.properties) makes a wrong assumption about the location of ant.jar, causing the build to fail.

I need to override it like this:
ant -Dfile.reference.ant.jar=/usr/share/java/ant.jar to succeed.

without that override, the build complains
&quot;package org.apache.tools.bzip2 does not exist&quot; (and others meant to be in ant.jar) for the code in src/org/opensolaris/opengrok/analysis/archive/

I&apos;m not sure whether it really is necessary to copy the ant.jar into the sourcetree (gets copied to dist/lib) - so I suggest to add a blurp about this to the build documentation at http://hub.opensolaris.org/bin/view/Project+opengrok/builddescription
(i.e. &quot;If you get errors like »package org.apache.tools.bzip2 does not exist«, pass the property file.reference.ant.jar pointing to the location of ant.jar on the commandline. For example: ant -Dfile.reference.ant.jar=/usr/share/java/ant.jar&quot; or something like that in better english)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>74771</commentid>
            <who name="Lubos Kosco">Lubos.Kosco</who>
            <bug_when>2010-06-25 05:49:14 +0000</bug_when>
            <thetext>weird
again a thing that works for me well ;)

let&apos;s do this - I am in swan, if your build machine is in swan, please contact me internally and I can login and test out building

I am using ant 1.7.1 (lately 1.8.0) and JDK 1.6.20 to get the build done without any issues

I build on latest OpenSolaris, Windows Vista, Debian stable. I also build on S10u3 patched to latest, but that involved a lot of manual setups so might not be trivial.

(what is your env? or if you point me to your swan system I&apos;ll check it ...)

Note that if you will not package ant.jar, then gzip/bzip/tgz analyzer will be broken and opengrok will just silently crash on analyzing these files ... (I think we had a bug on this, we just need to figure out a check on classloader, but it had low priority, since our builds just work(tm) ;) )

hmm?
L</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>74788</commentid>
            <who name="Christian Lohmaier">cloph</who>
            <bug_when>2010-06-25 11:58:04 +0000</bug_when>
            <thetext>No swan - my system is Mandriva 2010 - I&apos;m not using netbeans (netbeans is not installed at all) 

ant version is 1.7.1 JDK is 1.6.0_16

&quot;ant -diagnostics |grep ant.jar&quot; results in

java.class.path : /usr/share/java/ant.jar:/usr/share/java/ant-launcher.jar:/usr/share/java/ant/ant-nodeps.jar:/usr/lib/jvm/java/lib/tools.jar

And that doesn&apos;t match netbean&apos;s assumption that it is below ANT_HOME/lib (ant.home is /usr/share/ant here)

(for actually building opengrok, I additionally specify -lib /usr/share/java/JFlex.jar that then also is added to java.class.path)

And I got no problem with packing it and overriding it on the commandline (before filing the issue, I did a google search and find some old posts on the opengrok lists, so such a hint might help others)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>74792</commentid>
            <who name="Lubos Kosco">Lubos.Kosco</who>
            <bug_when>2010-06-25 13:26:19 +0000</bug_when>
            <thetext>ah ... Mandriva ...
wondering if RHEL will have the same prob

both Debian, OpenSolaris and unpacked ant installations have ant.jar in lib, in /usr/share/java they have symlinks to jars (and ant run uses ant.home=/usr/share/ant which has lib)

well, I&apos;ll try to think about some workaround, but till then just e.g. create a symlink lib which would point to the same dir
( ln -s /usr/share/java/ /usr/share/java/lib )
(I know, evil, but fast ;) )
OR have a separate ant installation which fulfills this assumption

(wondering if this is a packaging bug in Mandriva)


I am not sure if it would make sense adding another reference to ant.home/ant.jar
mhmmm ....
(after all I hope we will move to maven soon ;) )</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>74793</commentid>
            <who name="Lubos Kosco">Lubos.Kosco</who>
            <bug_when>2010-06-25 13:35:39 +0000</bug_when>
            <thetext>and you know what

try running ant just like e.g.:

opengrok_src_dir $ ant -lib /usr/share/java/  clean jar

wondering if above will pickup correct ant dir ... since 
and uses ant.library.dir and that should be correct and it should be set before we try to override it ... 
and if nothing above will pickup all jars and they all should be in classpath now ... (it might work ;) )

just a silly idea</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>74794</commentid>
            <who name="Christian Lohmaier">cloph</who>
            <bug_when>2010-06-25 13:43:44 +0000</bug_when>
            <thetext>Oh no, rather than creating symlinks bypassing the package manager, I prefer passing the corresponding property to ant when building, overriding the netbeans.properties.

That is also way better than installing a seperate ant just for building opengrok :-)

another reference to ant.home/ant.jar won&apos;t help for my case, since it is not in ant.home (/usr/share/ant), but /usr/share/java/

as for netbeans: 
$ urpmf /ant.jar |grep netb
netbeans-java2:/usr/share/netbeans/java2/ant/lib/ant.jar

i.e. installing netbeans would bring its own ant.jar. And very likely then the netbeans.properties would set ant.home to the netbeans one, and then it would find ant.jar at the expected location.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>74795</commentid>
            <who name="Lubos Kosco">Lubos.Kosco</who>
            <bug_when>2010-06-25 13:46:33 +0000</bug_when>
            <thetext>:)

on debian it works even without netbeans
so I tend to think it might be a packaging problem on Mandriva ;)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>74796</commentid>
            <who name="Christian Lohmaier">cloph</who>
            <bug_when>2010-06-25 13:52:15 +0000</bug_when>
            <thetext>And no, just specifying -lib /usr/share/java won&apos;t work (already tried before filing the bug) - it would pick up JFlex.jar, but the ant.jar still gets overridden - at least when using verbose I see &quot;dropping /usr/share/ant/lib/ant.jar from path as it doesn&apos;t exist&quot;

Well, /might/ be a packaging problem, but so far opengrok is the first to trigger it :-) (OTOH I don&apos;t build that many ant based projects)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>

</bugzilla>