<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<!DOCTYPE bugzilla SYSTEM "http://defect.opensolaris.org/bz/bugzilla.dtd">

<bugzilla version="3.6.5"
          urlbase="http://defect.opensolaris.org/bz/"
          
          maintainer="website-admin@opensolaris.org"
>

    <bug>
          <bug_id>18601</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2011-06-22 19:33:00 +0000</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>IgnoredNames.java should have two lists -- one for files, one for directories</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2012-02-21 21:31:15 +0000</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>2</classification_id>
          <classification>Development</classification>
          <product>opengrok</product>
          <component>indexer</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>ANY/Generic</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CAUSEKNOWN</bug_status>
          
          
          <see_also>http://defect.opensolaris.org/bz/show_bug.cgi?id=19180</see_also>
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>major</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>---</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Doug McLaren">dougmc+opensolaris</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Vladimir Kotal">vladimir.kotal</assigned_to>
          <cc>Lubos.Kosco</cc>
    
    <cc>opengrok-dev</cc>
    
    <cc>seadog1234567890</cc>
    
    <cc>vladimir.kotal</cc>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>83813</commentid>
            <who name="Doug McLaren">dougmc+opensolaris</who>
            <bug_when>2011-06-22 19:33:16 +0000</bug_when>
            <thetext>In the course of my figuring out why opengrok 0.10 wouldn&apos;t index all my files, I found two different problems that caused the issue.

The simplest problem was that opengrok wasn&apos;t indexing anything in our directories called &quot;tags&quot;.  (Combined with the other problem, it wasn&apos;t immediately apparent that anything in a directory called &quot;tags&quot; was skipped, but eventually it became clear.)

(The other problem will be the subject of another defect.)

In any event, the ctags program will create a file called &quot;tags&quot;, so it makes sense to ignore these files, but there&apos;s no reason that I&apos;m aware of to ignore a directory called tags.

Therefore, I suggest that IgnoredNames.java have two lists rather than one -- one list is a list of files to be ignored, and the other list is a list of directories to be ignored.  (There may also need to be some other code changes -- when the code actually checks to see if a file name should be ignored, it might have to tell the method that this is a file or it&apos;s a directory -- but that should be pretty obvious.)

For my own use, I&apos;m simply recompiling IgnoredNames.java to not skip anything named &quot;tags&quot;, but a proper fix is likely what I suggested above.

Also, some documentation on this list might be appropriate, or perhaps some way to customize the default list without recompiling.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>84446</commentid>
            <who name="Lubos Kosco">Lubos.Kosco</who>
            <bug_when>2011-07-21 13:28:44 +0000</bug_when>
            <thetext>Trond :) 

me is affected too! 
and me not like it

what will do ?

:-D

but seriously, this is a prob, I wasted 2 hours since I couldn&apos;t find my semantic tag sources which live in a directory called tags ;)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>86261</commentid>
            <who name="Vladimir Kotal">vladimir.kotal</who>
            <bug_when>2012-02-21 21:30:40 +0000</bug_when>
            <thetext>We will need to figure out what to do with the -i option since it is also generic.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>

</bugzilla>