<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<!DOCTYPE bugzilla SYSTEM "http://defect.opensolaris.org/bz/bugzilla.dtd">

<bugzilla version="3.6.5"
          urlbase="http://defect.opensolaris.org/bz/"
          
          maintainer="website-admin@opensolaris.org"
>

    <bug>
          <bug_id>342</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2008-01-04 12:02:00 +0000</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>RFE: linking projects with muliple paths</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2008-08-31 03:06:22 +0000</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>2</classification_id>
          <classification>Development</classification>
          <product>opengrok</product>
          <component>indexer</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>Other</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>ACCEPTED</bug_status>
          
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P4</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>---</target_milestone>
          <dependson>341</dependson>
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Hemang Lavana">HemangLavana</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Trond Norbye">trond.norbye</assigned_to>
          
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>945</commentid>
            <who name="Hemang Lavana">HemangLavana</who>
            <bug_when>2008-01-04 12:02:23 +0000</bug_when>
            <thetext>Hi,

Currently you can only link one path to an opengrok project. I think of a project as one or more modules necessary for me to get my work done. In that sense, I may want to link multiple paths from multiple locations for my project. And, it is also possible that I may reference a single path in multiple projects.

Consider the following directory structure of my SRC_ROOT (contrived example):


+ SRC_ROOT
___+ linux
______+ bin
______+ docs
______+ src
___+ tcl
______+ bin
______+ docs
______+ src

I would like to create two projects say:
(a) &quot;all-srcs&quot; which refers to everything under to linux/src and tcl/src,
(b) &quot;tcl-srcs+docs&quot; which refers to everything under tcl/src and tcl/docs.

Note that the &quot;tcl/srcs&quot; path is part of both the projects. If opengrok projects supports this, then I can see lot of benefits to it. I don&apos;t have to create toplevel directories under SRC_ROOT called &quot;all-srcs&quot; and &quot;tcl-srcs+docs&quot; and checkout a snapshot of corresponding paths one more time under these directories. So as a result my search queries will not return multiple results for the same entry and more additional diskspace will not be required for SRC_ROOT and DATA_ROOT.

On the UI side, it should not only allow searches by selected one or more projects but it should also provide a xref link for each project. For example, clicking on xref link for &quot;all-srcs&quot; would load a page listing xref pages corresponding to linux/src and tcl/src paths. Similarly, on the xref pages, it should provide an additional checkbox to limit the search by project name with which the file or directory is associated.

On the implementation side, I think that there could be a single global index for all the projects. The opengrok indexer should mark each path with corresponding project name if it doesn&apos;t already do that. And the spellchecker module can be modified to limit suggestions by specified project name. This way you still have a single master index and specifying the &quot;project:&lt;name&gt;&quot; term in the search criteria should make it behave like mini-opengrok instance.

You can find the original discussion at:

http://www.opensolaris.org/jive/thread.jspa?threadID=48378&amp;tstart=0

It would be great if opengrok projects can provide these capabilities.

Thanks,
Hemang.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>11518</commentid>
            <who name="Trond Norbye">trond.norbye</who>
            <bug_when>2008-08-31 03:06:22 +0000</bug_when>
            <thetext>We could add multiple projects for each file in the &quot;project-field&quot; for the file. I am not sure how this will affect the generated URLS for these symbols.. this needs more analysis to figure out.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>

</bugzilla>