<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<!DOCTYPE bugzilla SYSTEM "http://defect.opensolaris.org/bz/bugzilla.dtd">

<bugzilla version="3.6.5"
          urlbase="http://defect.opensolaris.org/bz/"
          
          maintainer="website-admin@opensolaris.org"
>

    <bug>
          <bug_id>8342</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2009-04-22 12:31:00 +0000</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Matching substrings aren&apos;t considered matches</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2009-10-25 20:00:28 +0000</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>2</classification_id>
          <classification>Development</classification>
          <product>opengrok</product>
          <component>webapp</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>ANY/Generic</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>NEW</bug_status>
          
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P2</priority>
          <bug_severity>major</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>---</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Curt Cox">curtcox</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Trond Norbye">trond.norbye</assigned_to>
          <cc>knut.hatlen</cc>
    
    <cc>Lubos.Kosco</cc>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>36342</commentid>
            <who name="Curt Cox">curtcox</who>
            <bug_when>2009-04-22 12:31:03 +0000</bug_when>
            <thetext>Searching for football, a novice would expect football_scores to be in the matching results, but it isn&apos;t.  Instead, the user has to search on football* to get the desired results.  There is some help available on help.jsp, but since this is probably a common mistake, why not add a few search syntax notes to the ample free space on the search page?  Another option would be to use the space to show search feedback messages like:

   Showing matches for &quot;football&quot;.  To also show matches for &quot;football_scores&quot;, and &quot;football_matches&quot;, use &quot;football*&quot;.   

The quoted texts above would all be links.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>50363</commentid>
            <who name="Lubos Kosco">Lubos.Kosco</who>
            <bug_when>2009-09-21 13:18:08 +0000</bug_when>
            <thetext>hi
I just pushed an example to help page for your use case
see trunk
changeset 849	b53ca0b26638

I am not sure on those suggestions.
Current ones show suggestions for spell checking only. We don&apos;t have any other logic (besides enclosing special chars into &quot;&quot; ).

I cannot quite imagine under what circumstances opengrok should show the sample &quot;blah*&quot; ... it doesn&apos;t know you want to search for substrings.
The other thing is, that wildcard is by default only on for right. To have the left wildcard working you need to have a special index created with option -a ...

If you got ideas how opengrok can guess the intent for searching for substrings, then share them, otherwise above help message should be enough, hmm ?

--
L</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>54105</commentid>
            <who name="Knut Anders Hatlen">knut.hatlen</who>
            <bug_when>2009-10-25 20:00:28 +0000</bug_when>
            <thetext>I&apos;m not sure it would make sense for symbol search, but at least for full text search we could make the tokenizer add the tokens &quot;football&quot;, &quot;scores&quot; and &quot;football_scores&quot; when it encounters &quot;football_scores&quot;. We&apos;d just have to define a set of separator characters (perhaps any non-alphanumeric char?). Of course, this wouldn&apos;t allow you to search for &quot;foot&quot; and expect it to return &quot;football&quot;.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>

</bugzilla>