<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<!DOCTYPE bugzilla SYSTEM "http://defect.opensolaris.org/bz/bugzilla.dtd">

<bugzilla version="3.6.5"
          urlbase="http://defect.opensolaris.org/bz/"
          
          maintainer="website-admin@opensolaris.org"
>

    <bug>
          <bug_id>2015</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2008-05-22 00:49:00 +0000</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Repository with symlinks causes warnings in &quot;quiet&quot; mode</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2008-08-26 13:09:44 +0000</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>2</classification_id>
          <classification>Development</classification>
          <product>opengrok</product>
          <component>indexer</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>ANY/Generic</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>Solaris</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P4</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>---</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Peter Bray">pdb_ml</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Trond Norbye">trond.norbye</assigned_to>
          
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>7212</commentid>
            <who name="Peter Bray">pdb_ml</who>
            <bug_when>2008-05-22 00:49:02 +0000</bug_when>
            <thetext>My mercurial repositories have several checked-in symbolic links (symlinks), these are usually to wrapper scripts in the same directory (ie one wrapper script implements several commands).

The following code fragment from IndexDatabase.java, highlights line 447 which unconditionally prints a warning when encountering a symlink which it doesn&apos;t like (ie most of them). 


    private boolean accept(File file) { 
      // Deleted code 
           if (!file.getAbsolutePath().equals(file.getCanonicalPath())) {
                System.err.println(&quot;Warning: ignored link &quot; + file.getAbsolutePath() +
                        &quot; -&gt; &quot; + file.getCanonicalPath());
                return false;
            }
      // Deleted code 
    }

This code should possibly use isVerbose() if it has access to it (unverified). I noted that verbose and quiet are paired (ie quiet = ! verbose) compared with other projects which have multi-level debugging/error-logging infrastructures.

My problem (is it is) is that in cron I&apos;d like to run &quot;run-quiet.sh&quot; or an equalivant using the &quot;-q&quot; option, and it not complain about symlinks that are part of the repository being indexed. I could filter the output and remove lines matching this warning, but it seems like something that should be looked at.

Looking at the project, it is probably worth having even simple logging framework, to remove all the direct usage of System.err.*() and allow more control over logging levels. A simple static interface like Log.Debug(), Log.Info(), Log.Notice(), *|* Log.Warning(), Log.Error(), Log.FatalError()
or the like (with the current -v | -q divide suggested by the *|*) would probably not take long to implement, and allow more standardised reporting that is amenable to future enhancement.

Also there maybe better ways to handle symlinks that are part of repositories, especially those to other files (or directories) within the repository ((ie internal symlinks)).

Thoughts/Comments Welcomed</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>7330</commentid>
            <who name="Trond Norbye">trond.norbye</who>
            <bug_when>2008-05-27 02:23:52 +0000</bug_when>
            <thetext>The intention of the -q flag is to get rid of the normal progress output, but this is a warning message and should not be removed by the -q flag.

We should probably add a configuration variable if links are allowed or not.

Jan Ståle Berg have a patch queued that replace the printing to stdout/err with a logging framework, so you can expect that to be fixed in the nearby future.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>11140</commentid>
            <who name="Trond Norbye">trond.norbye</who>
            <bug_when>2008-08-26 13:09:44 +0000</bug_when>
            <thetext>Fixed in changeset:   320:3bb0455186c3</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>

</bugzilla>