<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<!DOCTYPE bugzilla SYSTEM "http://defect.opensolaris.org/bz/bugzilla.dtd">

<bugzilla version="3.6.5"
          urlbase="http://defect.opensolaris.org/bz/"
          
          maintainer="website-admin@opensolaris.org"
>

    <bug>
          <bug_id>6082</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2009-01-12 15:34:00 +0000</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Source control configuration documentation is not adequate</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2012-01-27 13:22:45 +0000</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>2</classification_id>
          <classification>Development</classification>
          <product>opengrok</product>
          <component>doc</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>Other</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>Linux</op_sys>
          <bug_status>INCOMPLETE</bug_status>
          
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>major</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>---</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Curt Cox">curtcox</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Vladimir Kotal">vladimir.kotal</assigned_to>
          <cc>vladimir.kotal</cc>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24974</commentid>
            <who name="Curt Cox">curtcox</who>
            <bug_when>2009-01-12 15:34:52 +0000</bug_when>
            <thetext>I couldn&apos;t find any documentation telling how to set up OpenGrok to use a source control system.  If such documentation exists, it needs to be easier to find.  Ideally a running OpenGrok instance would have some sort of repository configuration screen that allowed authorized users to specify repository URLs.

The documentation for running OpenGrok without using any source control repositories is also outdated and incomplete.  However, I was able to get that portion running relatively quickly, so in a certain sense it is good enough.

The easier it is to get started, the more users you will get.

Thanks,
Curt</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>86134</commentid>
            <who name="Vladimir Kotal">vladimir.kotal</who>
            <bug_when>2012-01-25 14:11:52 +0000</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #0)
&gt; I couldn&apos;t find any documentation telling how to set up OpenGrok to use a
&gt; source control system.  If such documentation exists, it needs to be easier to
&gt; find.  Ideally a running OpenGrok instance would have some sort of repository
&gt; configuration screen that allowed authorized users to specify repository URLs.

By itself OpenGrok does not perform the setup of the source code repositories. This is to be done by the user - both for the initial setup and also for periodic synchronization.

The only point when OpenGrok needs to contact the repository is when the repository is remote (e.g. created by CVS checkout) and history lookup is performed.
 
&gt; The documentation for running OpenGrok without using any source control
&gt; repositories is also outdated and incomplete.  However, I was able to get that
&gt; portion running relatively quickly, so in a certain sense it is good enough.

Where is this documentation located ?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>86135</commentid>
            <who name="Vladimir Kotal">vladimir.kotal</who>
            <bug_when>2012-01-25 14:18:59 +0000</bug_when>
            <thetext>I just pushed the following change which clarifies some of the SCM repository handling questions:

changeset:   1298:5d1668919fb3
tag:         tip
user:        Vladimir Kotal &lt;Vladimir.Kotal@oracle.com&gt;
date:        Wed Jan 25 15:17:01 2012 +0100

description:
	README needs some hairdresser attention


Please take a look if the README is more helpful now.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>

</bugzilla>